A Guide to the Records of the Office of the Vice President for Academic Affairs and the Office of the Vice President for Special Projects, Alfred Krebs, 1963-1976
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Records of the Office of the Vice President for Academic Affairs and the Office of the Vice President for Special Projects, Alfred Krebs, 1963-1976
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
RG 5/1/2/1
This collection has digitized material available online.
7 Cubic Feet; 7 boxes
The collection consists primarily of the correspondence and other materials of Alfred Krebs in his capacity as Vice President for Special Projects (1975-1976). The collection also includes materials from his period as Interim Vice President for Academic Affairs (1972-1975). His duties as Vice President for Special Projects included university financial functions, chairmanship of the Computer Committee, Systems Development, Institutional Research, and the coordination of the Equal Employment Opportunity and Affirmative Action Programs. There are materials regarding such subjects as consulting projects, cases from the Judicial Review committee, the Telecommunication Committee, and the University Council. Correspondence and other documents detail the formation and management of the Computer Committtee, the creation and implementation of an Affirmative Action Plan,and procedures for implementing Title IX regulations.
Krebs, Alfred H., 1920-2012
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The collection was acquired by Special Collections prior to 2002.
Alternate Form Available
This collection has digitized material available online.
Biographical Note
Alfred H. Krebs (1920-2012) earned a bachelor's, master's, and Ph.D. from Cornell University and served in the U.S. Army during World War II. He taught agricultural education at the University of Illinois at Urbana–Champaign and the University of Maryland before joining the faculty of Virginia Tech in 1969. Krebs served as head of agricultural education and director of the summer school program. He became the Assistant Vice President for Academic Affairs in 1972, the Vice President for Special Projects in 1975, and Vice President of Administration in 1977. Alfred Krebs retired from Virginia Tech in August of 1981.
Source: In memoriam: Alfred H. Krebs, former vice president for administration, Virginia Tech, January 5, 2012.
Scope and Content
The collection consists primarily of the correspondence and other materials of Alfred Krebs in his capacity as Vice President for Special Projects (1975-1976). The collection also includes materials from his period as Interim Vice President for Academic Affairs (1972-1975). His duties as Vice President for Special Projects included university financial functions, chairmanship of the Computer Committee, Systems Development, Institutional Research, and the coordination of the Equal Employment Opportunity and Affirmative Action Programs. There are materials regarding such subjects as consulting projects, cases from the Judicial Review committee, the Telecommunication Committee, and the University Council.
Correspondence and other documents detail the formation and management of the Computer Committtee, the creation and implementation of an Affirmative Action Plan,and procedures for implementing Title IX regulations.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by subject.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Faculty; University Archives; University History
Persons:
Krebs, Alfred H., 1920-2012
Organizations:
Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Contents List
This collection has digitized material available online.
- Accounting, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Administrative Conference, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Admissions, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Affirmative Action - General Correspondence EEO/AA, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 4-6)
- Affirmative Action Plan - Handicapped, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
- Affirmative Action Plan, 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 9-15)
- Affirmative Action WEL Copies, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 16-17)
- Agricultural Extension Service - Monthly Revenue Statements, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Agriculture and Life Sciences, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Alpha Omicron Circle, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Alpha Phi Omega, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- American Association of University Professors (AAUP), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- American Association of University Women (AAUW), 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- American Council on Education, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Architecture, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Arnold Air Society, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- College of Arts and Sciences - General Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- College of Arts and Sciences - Geophysics Program, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- Auditor, Internal, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Automated Data Processing (ADP), 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 30-31, Box 2, Folder 32-33)
- Automated Data Processing - Policy Committee, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Automated Information System (AIS), 1976-06 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Auxiliary Enterprises, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Bicentennial, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Board of Visitors, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 38-39)
- Budget Director, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 40-41)
- Bugle, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Building Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Buildings and Grounds, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Business, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Business Manager, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Campus Mail, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Capital Consortium, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Central Virginia Consortium, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Change of Academic Calendar (Ad Hoc Committee), 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Class of 1978, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- College Law Conference, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Commencement Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Commission on Faculty Affairs, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Commission on Graduate Studies and Research, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 55)
- Commission on Student Affairs, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Commission on Student Affairs, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 57-59)
- Committee on Patents, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Computer Committee, 1970-1976 (Box 2, Folder 61-63)
- Computer Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Computer Committee, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 65-66)
- Computer Services - University of Tennessee, Knoxville, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 67)
- Computer User's Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 68)
- Computerized Management Network, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 69)
- Computing Center - General Information, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 70-72, Box 3, Folder 73-75)
- Computing Center - General Information, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 76-78)
- Computing Center - Hardware/Software, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 79-80)
- Computing Center - IMS Personnel Responsibilities, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 81)
- Computing Center Log, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 82)
- Computing Center - Personnel, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 83)
- Computer Committee - Performance Standards, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 84)
- Conferences, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 85)
- Consulting Group - Computing Center, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 86)
- Consulting - Not Approved, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 87)
- Consulting Policy, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 88)
- Consulting - Ratified by the Board, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 89-93)
- Consulting - Ratified by the Board, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 94)
- Consulting - Ratified by the Board, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 95-98)
- Control Data Corporation, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 99)
- Copyright Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 100)
- Corps of Cadets, 1975-1976 (Box 3, Folder 101)
- Deans, Directors, and Department Heads Listing, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 102)
- Division of the Budget, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 103)
- Doctoral Fellowship Program for Minority Virginians, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 104)
- Education, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 105)
- Education, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 106)
- Education, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 107)
- EDUCOM, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 108)
- Engineering, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 109)
- Exchange Visitor Program, 1973-1977 (Box 4, Folder 110)
- Extension Division, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 111)
- Faculty Retreat, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 112)
- Faculty Senate, 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 113)
- Fine Arts Committee, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 114)
- First Aid Crew and Rescue Squad, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 115)
- Gay Student Alliance, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 116)
- General Consortium - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 117)
- Graduate School, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 118)
- Higher Education and National Affairs: Bulletin, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 119)
- Home Economics, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 120)
- Honor System, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 121)
- Inauguration, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 122)
- Information Exchange Procedures (IEP), 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 123-124)
- Information Services, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 125)
- Institutional Research, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 126)
- Interfraternity Council/Panhellenic Council, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 127)
- International Student Orientation and Housing (Subcommittee), 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 128)
- International Travel, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 129-130)
- Judicial Review Committee, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 131)
- Judicial Review Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 132)
- Judicial Review Committee, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 133-135)
- Judicial Review Committee, Cases A-L, 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 136)
- Judicial Review Committee, Cases A-L, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 137)
- Judicial Review Committee, Cases A-L, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 138-142)
- Judicial Review Committee, Cases A-L, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 143)
- Judicial Review Committee, Cases M-Z, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 144)
- Judicial Review Committee, Cases M-Z, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 145-148)
- Kroger Intern Program, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 149)
- Learning Resource Center, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 150)
- Library, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 151)
- McElvery, Roger M., 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 152)
- Miscellaneous, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 153)
- Mortar Board, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 154)
- NACUBO, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 155)
- National Association of State Universities and Land Grand Colleges, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 156)
- National Association of State Universities and Land Grand Colleges, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 157)
- National University Conference on Hunger Committee, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 158)
- National Wooden Pallet and Container Association, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 159)
- Norfolk Area Medical Center, 1973-1975 (Box 5, Folder 160)
- Northern Virginia Consortium, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 161)
- Oak Ridge Associated Universities, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 162)
- Occupational Health and Safety, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 163)
- Occupational Health and Safety Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 164)
- Open House Study Committee, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 165)
- Personnel, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 166-168)
- Phi Beta Kappa, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 169)
- Phi Kappa Phi, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 170)
- President, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 171)
- Public Information Commission - American Vocational Association, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 172)
- Radiation Safety Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 173)
- Registrar, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 174)
- Reports and Recordkeeping Requirements, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 175, Box 6, Folder 176-177)
- Research Division, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 178)
- Residence Hall Federation, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 179)
- Scheduling and Registration Committee, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 180)
- School Law Newsletter, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 181)
- Society for College and University Planning, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 182)
- Solar Energy Research Institute - National Solar Energy Research Consortium, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 183-184)
- Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 185)
- Southern Regional Education Board, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 186)
- Space, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 187)
- Space Needs Assessment and Forecast for the University Committee (SNAFU), 1975 (Box 6, Folder 188)
- State, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 189)
- State - Accounting System, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 190)
- State - Attorney General, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 191)
- State - Secretary of Education, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 192)
- State Computer Resource Planning, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 193)
- State Council of Higher Education for Virginia, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 194)
- State Government Management, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 195)
- State Office on Volunteerism, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 196)
- State Vocational Education Advisory Council, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 197)
- Student Budget Board, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 198-199)
- Student Constitutional Affairs Board, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 200)
- Student Government Association, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 201)
- Telecommunications Committee, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 202)
- Telecommunications - General Correspondence, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 203)
- Telecommunications - HEAR Project, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 204)
- Telecommunications - Microwave Link, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 205)
- Telecommunications - Planning for Public Service Satellite Applications, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 206)
- Telecommunications - Program Master Plan, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 207-209)
- Telecommunications - Surplus Two-Way Radio Channels, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 210)
- Telecommunications - Virginia Public Telecommunications Council, 1974-1976 (Box 6, Folder 211-213)
- Telecommunications - VPI & SU/Blacksburg Cable Television, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 214)
- Title IX, 1975-1976 (Box 6, Folder 215)
- Title IX - Athletic Programs, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 216-217)
- Title IX, Association for Intercollegiate Athletics for Women, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 218)
- Title IX, Evaluation, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 219)
- Title IX, Rules and Regulations, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 220)
- Town of Blacksburg, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 221)
- Traffic Appeals Subcommittee - Judicial Review Committee, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 222)
- Treasurer's Office, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 223)
- University Committee on International Programs, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 224)
- University Copy Equipment Review Committee, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 225)
- University Council, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 226-227)
- University Council, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 228-230)
- University Council, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 231)
- University Research Association, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 232)
- Valley Consortium, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 233)
- Veterinary Medicine, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 234)
- Vice-President for Academic Affairs, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 235-237)
- Vice-President for Academic Affairs, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 238-239)
- Vice-President for Special Projects, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 240)
- Vice-President for Special Projects, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 241)
- Vice-President for Student Affairs, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 242-244)
- Virginia Freedom of Information Act, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 245)
- Virginia Public Interest Research, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 246)
- Virginia Tech Alumni Association, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 247)
- Virginia Tech Student Aid Association, Inc., 1976 (Box 7, Folder 248)
- Virginia Tech Union, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 249)
- Virginia Tidewater Consortium, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 250)
- VPI Extension Division, Monthly Revenue Statements, 1966-1972 (Box 7, Folder 251-252)
- Water Resource Research Center, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 253)
- Western Region Consortium, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 254)
- Xerox Education Foundation, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 255)